Michael Alpert collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 7: North American field recordings
  - Isaak Varshavsky, Leonid Verbitsky, 1981-1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0162; Personnel: Isaak Varshavsky, Leonid Verbitsky, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Queens Jewish Center.; Alpert 306; 1 sound cassette
  - Italya, September 25, 2008, afc2017048_dc001; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Italian American Museum.; Alpert 309; 1 WAV
  - Khaya Sherman, October 25, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0166; Personnel: Khaya Sherman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 318-319; 1 sound cassette
  - Jacob Shafer I, May 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0169; Personnel: Jacob Shafer, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Home.; Alpert 335-336; 1 sound cassette
  - Jacob Shafer II, May 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0170; Personnel: Jacob Shafer, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Home.; Alpert 337; 1 sound cassette
  - Black Sea Restaurant, May 27, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0171; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Alpert 338-339; 1 sound cassette
  - Roitman, Surdis, Black Sea Restaurant, May 27, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0172; Personnel: Roitman, Surdis, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Black Sea Restaurant, Fairfax Avenue.; Alpert 340; 1 sound cassette
  - Soviet Jewish Record Series (City Lore), undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0173; Personnel: Shashmaqam and more.; Recording location: City Lore.; Alpert 341-342; 1 sound cassette
  - Shimen Zaks- I, May 28, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0176; Personnel: Shimen Zaks, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 349-350; 1 sound cassette
  - Shimen Zaks- II, May 28, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0177; Personnel: Shimen Zaks, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 351-352; 1 sound cassette
  - Gorenshtein Party I, May 29, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0178; Personnel: David Gorenshtein, Fruma Gorenshtein, Pola Vaynshteyn, Bella Posy, Lev Faynberg, Fanya Faynberg, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 357-358; 1 sound cassette
  - Gorenshtein Party II, May 29, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0179; Personnel: David Gorenshtein, Fruma Gorenshtein, Pola Vaynshteyn, Bella Posy, Lev Faynberg, Fanya Faynberg, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 359-360; 1 sound cassette
  - Lyudmila Lantsman; Zavelions, May 30, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0180; Personnel: Lyudmila Lantsman, Zavelions.; Alpert 361-362; 1 sound cassette
  - Shura Gorshteyn; Meir Rabranvsky, May 31, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0181; Personnel: Shura Gorshteyn, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 363-364; 1 sound cassette
  - Shimen Zaks- I, August 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0183; Personnel: Shimen Zaks, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Home.; Alpert 367-368; 1 sound cassette
  - Shimen Zaks- II, August 25, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0184; Personnel: Shimen Zaks, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Home.; Alpert 369; 1 sound cassette
  - Shimen Zaks- III, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0185; Personnel: Shimen Zaks, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Home.; Alpert 370-371; 1 sound cassette
  - LA, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0188; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Los Angeles.; Alpert 379-380; 1 sound cassette
  - Isaac Sadigursky, February 27, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0192; Personnel: Isaac Sadigursky, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Westlake Village, California (his home).; Alpert 385-386; 1 sound cassette
  - Georgians, May 16, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0194; Recording location: Forest Hills, New York.; Alpert 389-390; 1 sound cassette
  - Moyshe Nussbaum- I, January 18, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0214; Personnel: Moyshe Nussbaum, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Yugntruf Event by Judy Helfand, East Village, New York City.; Alpert 428-429; 1 sound cassette
  - Moyshe Nussbaum- II, January 18, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0215; Personnel: Moyshe Nussbaum, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Yugntruf Event by Judy Helfand, East Village, New York City.; Alpert 430-431; 1 sound cassette
  - Moyshe Nussbaum- III, January 18, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0216; Personnel: Moyshe Nussbaum, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Yugntruf Event by Judy Helfand, East Village, New York City.; Alpert 432-433; 1 sound cassette
  - Moyshe Nussbaum- I, February 2, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0217; Personnel: Moyshe Nussbaum, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Gottesman's (Bronx).; Alpert 434-435; 1 sound cassette
  - Moyshe Nussbaum- II; Bronx, February 2- August 28, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0218; Personnel: Moyshe Nussbaum, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Gottesman's (Bronx).; Alpert 436; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronx, August 28, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0219; Alpert 437-438; 1 sound cassette
  - Bronx- II, August 28, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0220; Alpert 439; 1 sound cassette
  - Shorefront "New" Klezmer, August 9, 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0230; Alpert 456-457; 1 sound cassette
  - Liza Khorunzhaya, May 24, 2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0231; Personnel: Liza Khorunzhaya, Susan Lerner, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Home in "The Unichirlochen," Hollywood Court.; Alpert 458-459; 1 sound cassette
  - Louis Moses Seder, 1959, AFC 2017/048: SR0232; Personnel: Louis Moses.; Recording location: Ioannina Romaniot Seder, New York.; Alpert 460; 1 sound cassette
  - Bardejov, Slovakia, October 7, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0233; Personnel: Meyer Spira, Danny Soyer, Rob, Newman, MJA, Aviva Weintraub, Joel Rubin.; Recording location: Meyer Spira's Apt?; Alpert 461-462; 1 sound cassette
  - Joe Alpert, October 1976, AFC 2017/048: SR0248; Personnel: Joe Alpert, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 490-491; 1 sound cassette
  - Joe Alpert, 1978, AFC 2017/048: SR0249; Personnel: Joe Alpert, Mary Alpert, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 492-493; 1 sound cassette
  - Joe Alpert- I, January 1, 1981, AFC 2017/048: SR0250; Personnel: Joe Alpert.; Alpert 496; 1 sound cassette
  - Joe Alpert- II, November 24, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0251; Personnel: Joe Alpert, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 497; 1 sound cassette
  - Joe Alpert; Joe Alpert, Harry Kornetsky, November 4-21, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0252; Personnel: Joe Alpert, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Hebrew Home, Roslindale, Massachusetts.; Alpert 498-499; 1 sound cassette
  - Martin Kalisky- I, January 16, 1989, AFC 2017/048: SR0253; Personnel: Martin Kalisky, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 507-508; 1 sound cassette
  - Martin Kalisky- II, January 16, 1989, AFC 2017/048: SR0254; Personnel: Martin Kalisky, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 509; 1 sound cassette
  - Martin Kalisky, Jeff Warschauer, September 14, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0255; Personnel: Martin Kalisky, Jeff Warschauer.; Alpret 510; 1 sound cassette
  - Joe Alpert- I, May 29, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0256; Personnel: Joe Alpert, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 511-512; 1 sound cassette
  - Joe Alpert- II, May 29, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0257; Personnel: Joe Alpert, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 513-514; 1 sound cassette
  - Joe Alpert- II, July 3, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0258; Personnel: Joe Alpert, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Joe's Home.; Alpert 515-516; 1 sound cassette
  - Joe Alpert- III, July 3, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0259; Personnel: Joe Alpert, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 517-518; 1 sound cassette
  - Joe Alpert - IV, September 15, 1983-January 29, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0260; Personnel: Joe Alpert, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 519-520; 1 sound cassette
  - Joe Alpert; Etta Morrison, Benjidl Paul, Sylvia Morrison, Joe Alpert, May 12, 1981-March 27, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0261; Personnel: Joe Alpert, Etta Morrison, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 521-522; 1 sound cassette
  - Joe Alpert, November 23-24, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0262; Personnel: Joe Alpert, Etta Morrison, Sylvia Morrison, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Recuperative Center.; Alpert 523-524; 1 sound cassette
  - Joe Alpert, December 30, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0263; Personnel: Joe Alpert, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 527-528; 1 sound cassette
  - Joe Alpert, November 30, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0264; Personnel: Joe Alpert, Michael Alpert, Sue Foy.; Alpert 529; 1 sound cassette
  - Max Greenseid- I, July 28, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0265; Personnel: Max Greenseid, Dan (Rebecca) Greenseid, Leanne Greenseid, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: 61 Eastern Parkway, Brooklyn.; Alpert 530-531; 1 sound cassette
  - Max Greenseid- II, July 28, 1990, AFC 2017/048: SR0266; Personnel: Max Greenseid, Dan (Rebecca) Greenseid, Leanne Greenseid, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: 61 Eastern Parkway, Brooklyn.; Alpert 532-533; 1 sound cassette
  - Cele Robinson, November 23, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0267; Personnel: Cele Robinson, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Newton, Massachusetts.; Alpert 538-539; 1 sound cassette
  - Lenny Kornet, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0268; Personnel: Lenny Kornet, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 540; 1 sound cassette
  - Alpert Family; Lenny Kornet On the Road, May 1-2, 1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0269; Personnel: Alpert Family.; Recording location: Annabelle and Arthur Orenberg's, Lexington, Massachusetts.; Alpert 541-542; 1 sound cassette
  - Lenny Kornet On the Road- II, May 2, 1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0270; Personnel: Lenny Kornet, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: On the road.; Alpert 543-544; 1 sound cassette
  - Sonya Kruger- I, July 25, 1976, AFC 2017/048: SR0272; Personnel: Sonya Kruger, Nina Mendy, Devorah Sovsky.; Recording location: Sonya Kruger's home.; Alpert 546-547; 1 sound cassette
  - Sonya Kruger- II, July 25, 1976, AFC 2017/048: SR0273; Personnel: Sonya Kruger, Nina Mendy, Devorah Sovsky.; Recording location: Sonya Kruger's home.; Alpert 548; 1 sound cassette
  - Yiddish Folk Singers, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0287; Personnel: Itzik Gottesman, Beyle Gottesman.; Alpert 573-574; 1 sound cassette
  - Beyle Gottesman-Probe, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0289; Personnel: Beyle Gottesman.; Alpert 577-578; 1 sound cassette
  - Beyle Zingt Dray Lider, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0290; Personnel: Beyle Gottesman.; Alpert 579; 1 sound cassette
  - Beyle Gottesman, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0291; Personnel: Beyle Gottesman.; Alpert 580-581; 1 sound cassette
  - Beyle Gottesman Lider, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0292; Personnel: Beyle Gottesman.; Alpert 582; 1 sound cassette
  - Mume Beltse and Feter Yoyne, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0293; Personnel: Beyle and Yoyne Gottesman.; Alpert 583-584; 1 sound cassette
  - Sam Offen, November 7, 1979, AFC 2017/048: SR0295; Personnel: Sam Offen, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: JASA, West 83rd Street.; Alpert 586-587; 1 sound cassette
  - Bialystoker and Riverdale, January 9-28, 1980, AFC 2017/048: SR0297; Personnel: Frieda Youngstein, Celia Badash, Rosa Goodwine, Laura Jones, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Bialystoker Home, Riverdale Nursing Home.; Alpert 590-591; 1 sound cassette
  - Riverdale, February 4, 1980, AFC 2017/048: SR0298; Personnel: Rosa Goodwine, Ida Williams, Anna Thurmond, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Riverdale Nursing Home.; Alpert 592-593; 1 sound cassette
  - Gertrude Posner, March 6, 1980, AFC 2017/048: SR0299; Personnel: Gertrude Posner, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Bialystoker Home.; Alpert 594; 1 sound cassette
  - Rosa Goodwine, March 7, 1980, AFC 2017/048: SR0300; Personnel: Rosa Goodwine, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 595-596; 1 sound cassette
  - Tillie Gerrowitz, March 13, 1980, AFC 2017/048: SR0301; Personnel: Tillie Gerrowitz, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Bialystoker Home.; Alpert 597-598; 1 sound cassette
  - Rosa Goodwine, April 14, 1980, AFC 2017/048: SR0302; Personnel: Rosa Goodwine, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 599; 1 sound cassette
  - Bialystoker; Tillie Gerrowitz, April 10-June 4, 1980, AFC 2017/048: SR0303; Personnel: Frieda Youngstein, Celia Badash, Benny Botwinnik.; Recording location: Bialystoker Home.; Alpert 600-601; 1 sound cassette
  - Bialystoker; Practice Tape, April 1980, AFC 2017/048: SR0304; Personnel: Frieda Youngstein, Celia, Badash, Michael Alpert, Andy Statman.; Recording location: Bialystoker Home.; Alpert 602-603; 1 sound cassette
  - Megilleh, Brighton Beach, June 1981, AFC 2017/048: SR0305; Recording location: Brighton Beach.; Alpert 604-605; 1 sound cassette
  - Shaya Kirman, July 21, 1981, AFC 2017/048: SR0306; Personnel: Shaya Kirman, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Vancouver, British Columbia.; Alpert 606-607; 1 sound cassette
  - Day at Jay Feldman's; Nestor and Friends, February 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0307; Personnel: Jay Feldman, Jody Stecher, Stewart Mennin, Stuart Brotman, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Jay Feldman's.; Alpert 608-609; 1 sound cassette
  - Brighton Beach, 1982, AFC 2017/048: SR0308; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Brighton Beach.; Alpert 610-611; 1 sound cassette
  - Brighton Beach, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0310; Personnel: Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Brighton Beach.; Alpert 612-613; 1 sound cassette
  - Daisy Braverman, May 9, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0311; Personnel: Daisy Braverman, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Long Island Jewish Arts Festival.; Alpert 614; 1 sound cassette
  - Sephardic Fieldwork-2, June 19, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0312; Personnel: Susan Mann, Dianne Esses, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Sephardic Community Center, Brooklyn.; Alpert 615-616; 1 sound cassette
  - Sephardic Fieldwork-3, September 3, 1983, AFC 2017/048: SR0313; Personnel: Ezra Ashkenazi, Shlomo Levy, Joe Catton, Joseph Mohaddab.; Recording location: Sephardic Community Center, Brooklyn.; Alpert 617-618; 1 sound cassette
  - Long Island Jewish Arts Festival-I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0314; Recording location: Roza/Soso's house.; Alpert 619-620; 1 sound cassette
  - Long Island Jewish Arts Festival-II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0315; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Bronya Sakina.; Recording location: Long Island Jewish Arts Festival.; Alpert 621; 1 sound cassette
  - LA-Jewish Work Tape, August 1981, AFC 2017/048: SR0316; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Jerry Millstein.; Alpert 622-623; 1 sound cassette
  - Rabbi Harold Swiss-I, April 12, 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0320; Personnel: Rabbi Harold Swiss.; Recording location: Institute for Legal Careers.; Alpert 630; 1 sound cassette
  - Rabbi Harold Swiss-II, May 3, 1984-January 24, 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0321; Personnel: Rabbi Harold Swiss.; Recording location: Institute for Legal Careers.; Alpert 631-632; 1 sound cassette
  - Isaac Sene, August 1985, AFC 2017/048: SR0323; Personnel: Isaac Sene.; Alpert 635-636; 1 sound cassette
  - Mikhl Baran, January 27, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0324; Personnel: Mikhl Baran.; Alpert 637; 1 sound cassette
  - Hersch Eimer Minsky's-I, March 5, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0325; Personnel: Hersch Eimer, Nathan & Rokhl Minsky.; Alpert 638-639; 1 sound cassette
  - Hersch Eimer Minsky's-II, March 5, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0326; Personnel: Hersch Eimer, Nathan & Rokhl Minsky.; Alpert 640; 1 sound cassette
  - Charlotte Yiddish Institute-I, May 24, 1986, AFC 2017/048: SR0328; Personnel: Avrom Luski, Mike Baker.; Alpert 643-644; 1 sound cassette
  - Eddie Seroussi, May 11, 1987, AFC 2017/048: SR0332; Personnel: Eddie Seroussi.; Alpert 650; 1 sound cassette
  - Fairfax Singers, 1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0333; Personnel: Shura (Sore) Gorhsteyn.; Recording location: LA.; Alpert 651-652; 1 sound cassette
  - Michael Alpert on Around NY WNYC; Lubavitch on 103rd St-II, September 1988-1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0334; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Connie Blaszczyh.; Recording location: Radio Show WNYC.; Alpert 653-654; 1 sound cassette
  - Lubavitch on 103rd St-I, 1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0335; Recording location: 103rd St.; Alpert 655-656; 1 sound cassette
  - Miami Beach Rhumba I, January 15, 1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0336; Personnel: Tsunye Reimer, Yankl Gorelick, Itta Taub, Leib & Tencer (Montreal), Avreml Feldman.; Recording location: Chez Gaub, Miami Beach.; Alpert 657-658; 1 sound cassette
  - Yeremiye Hescheles-I, July 21, 1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0339; Personnel: Yeremiye Hescheles, Michael Alpert, Gottesmans.; Recording location: Gottesman's.; Alpert 663-664; 1 sound cassette
  - Louise Bilman-I, October 1992, AFC 2017/048: SR0340; Personnel: Louise Bilman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 665-666; 1 sound cassette
  - Louise Bilman-II, October 1992, AFC 2017/048: SR0341; Personnel: Louise Bilman, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 667; 1 sound cassette
  - Traditional Folk Artists of IJAFLI compiled, 1992, AFC 2017/048: SR0342; Personnel: Ken Gross Satmer Chassidic Orchestra, Ben Zion Moische Rosenberg, Michel & Papes Orchestra, Irina Fogelson, Eli Lipsker Chassidic Orchestra, Farid Dardashti, Middle Eastern Trio, Avram Pengas.; Alpert 668; 1 sound cassette
  - Larry Saunders, October 6, 1993, AFC 2017/048: SR0344; Personnel: Larry Saunders, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 671-672; 1 sound cassette
  - Yosl Weiss, June 1994, AFC 2017/048: SR0345; Personnel: Yosl Weiss, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 673; 1 sound cassette
  - Sam Wise, August 17, 1996, AFC 2017/048: SR0347; Personnel: Sam Wise, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Wildacres, Lil Switzerland, N.C.; Alpert 676-677; 1 sound cassette
  - George Caba-I, January 11, 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0348; Personnel: George Caba, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 678-679; 1 sound cassette
  - Yosef Weiss, May 26, 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0349; Personnel: Yosef Weiss, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 680-681; 1 sound cassette
  - Bessie, 1998, AFC 2017/048: SR0350; Personnel: Bessie, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Jewish Home and Hospice.; Alpert 682; 1 sound cassette
  - Moshe Rubin, October 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0357; Personnel: Moshe Rubin.; Alpert 695; 1 sound cassette
  - Yiddish Folksingers at Tonic, February 2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0358; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Zev Feldman, Josh Waletzky, Beyle Shechter-Gottesman, Nitse Rantz, Jeff Warschauer, Janet Leuchter, Itzik Gottesman.; Recording location: Tonic, NYC.; Alpert 696-697; 1 sound cassette
  - Bernie Uhr, December 26, 2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0359; Personnel: Bernie Uhr, Michael Alpert, Hankus Netsky.; Recording location: KlezKamp, Hilton Hotel, Cherry Hill, NJ, Rm 618.; Alpert 698-699; 1 sound cassette
  - Brona Levy, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0362; Personnel: Brona Levy.; Alpert 706; 1 sound cassette
  - Lider fun Bukovina, February 2003, AFC 2017/048: SR0366; Personnel: Beyle Gottesman, Itzik Gottesman.; Recording location: "Kavehoyz" NYC.; Alpert 711-712; 1 sound cassette
  - Eliezer Lieber, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0367; Personnel: Eliezer Lieber Shechter.; Alpert 713; 1 sound cassette
  - Elliot Eisenbach, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0368; Personnel: Elliot Eisenbach.; Recording location: Upper West Side, NYC either Michael or Elliot's apartment.; Alpert 714; 1 sound cassette
  - Rose Volk, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0369; Personnel: Rose Volk.; Recording location: Minneapolis, MN.; Alpert 715-716; 1 sound cassette
  - Volk-Schlamme-I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0370; Personnel: Rose Volk, Martha Schlamme.; Recording location: Minneapolis, MN.; Alpert 718; 1 sound cassette
  - Volk-Schlamme-II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0371; Personnel: Rose Volk, Martha Schlamme.; Recording location: Minneapolis, MN.; Alpert 719; 1 sound cassette
  - Jack Albert, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0373; Personnel: Jack Albert.; Alpert 722; 1 sound cassette
  - Jesus Rosaria Talks, 1990-1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0374; Personnel: Jesus Rosaria, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: YIVO.; Alpert 723-724; 1 sound cassette
  - Rose Damesek, Findley House Singers; Findley House Singers, Zena Krop, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0375; Personnel: Rose Damesek, Findley House Singers.; Recording location: Aishel Avraham HRE (Williamsburg, Brooklyn), Findley House (Bronx).; Alpert 725-726; 1 sound cassette
  - Rose Damesek-II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0376; Personnel: Rose Damesek, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Aishel Avraham HRE (Williamsburg, Brooklyn).; Alpert 727; 1 sound cassette
  - Tonic Concert-Generation of Yiddish Song, January 9, 2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0377; Personnel: Michael Alpert, Zev Feldman, Josh Waletzky, Beyle Shechter-Gottesman, Nitse Rantz, Jeff Warschauer, Janet Leuchter, Itzik Gottesman.; Recording location: Tonic, NYC.; Alpert 728-729; 1 sound cassette
  - Flory Jagoda; Jewish Accordion, Lebedinskaya, 1989, AFC 2017/048: SR0382; Personnel: Flory Jagoda.; Recording location: Glen Alexander Studio, Gaithersburg, MD.; Alpert 736-737; 1 sound cassette
  - Lillian Lux Burstein, March 11, 2001, AFC 2017/048: SR0384; Personnel: Lillian Lux Burstein, Michael Alpert, Joel Hoffman, Dorotea Hoffman.; Recording location: 2nd Ave Deli.; Alpert 740-741; 1 sound cassette
  - Paris to Kyiv and Brave Old World Rehearsal, 2000, AFC 2017/048: SR0391; Personnel: Julian Kytasty, Alexis Kochan, Richard Moody, Michael Alpert, Alan Bern, Stuart Brotman, Kurt Bjorling.; Recording location: Los Angeles.; Alpert 751-752; 1 sound cassette
  - German Goldenshteyn, April 19, 2002, AFC 2017/048: SR0392; Personnel: German Goldenshteyn, Michael Alpert, Mina Goldenshteyn.; Recording location: German and Mina's apartment, Avenue V, Brooklyn.; Alpert 753; 1 sound cassette
  - Majer Bogdanski, 1987-1988, AFC 2017/048: SR0393; Personnel: Majer Bogdanski, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: London.; Alpert 754-755; 1 sound cassette
  - Pauly Stein-I, December 12, 1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0394; Personnel: Pauly Stein, Lisa Stein, Laurie Stein, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 756-757; 1 sound cassette
  - Pauly Stein-II, December 12, 1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0395; Personnel: Pauly Stein, Lisa Stein, Laurie Stein, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 758-759; 1 sound cassette
  - Pauly Stein-III, December 13, 1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0396; Personnel: Pauly Stein, Lisa Stein, Laurie Stein, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 760-761; 1 sound cassette
  - Pauly Stein-IV, December 13, 1991, AFC 2017/048: SR0397; Personnel: Pauly Stein, Lisa Stein, Laurie Stein, Michael Alpert.; Alpert 762; 1 sound cassette
  - Comlosana, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0399; Recording location: Chicago.; Alpert 765-766; 1 sound cassette
  - Whad'Ya Know, NPR Show, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0402; Personnel: Michael Feldman.; Alpert 769; 1 sound cassette
  - Majer Bogdanski, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0403; Personnel: Majer Bogdanski, Michael Alpert, Woman.; Recording location: London.; Alpert 770; 1 sound cassette
  - Irving Berlin and More; Accordion, Serbian Song, Israeli Song, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0405; Side B: Personnel: Stuart Brotman, Barry Fisher, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Los Angeles.; Alpert 772-773; 1 sound cassette
  - Ferron; Nightingale Sometimes When the Moon is High, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0415; Personnel: Ferron.; Alpert 790-791; 1 sound cassette
  - Paloma Lopez-Gruninger, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0416; Personnel: Paloma Lopez-Grüninger.; Recording location: New York.; Alpert 792; 1 sound cassette
  - Solo Concert at Berkeley, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0418; Personnel: Mark Forry, Michael Alpert.; Recording location: Berkeley, CA.; Alpert 794-795; 1 sound cassette
  - Greek Radio-Yiddish, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0426; Alpert 808-809; 1 sound cassette
  - Ellis Island Orchestra-Anthology; Genia Patlan, August 13, 1981, AFC 2017/048: SR0430; Personnel: Stuart Brotman, Barry Fisher, R. Holmes, Stuart Mennin.; Alpert 816-817; 1 sound cassette
  - Chutzpah, April 20, 1978, AFC 2017/048: SR0437; Personnel: Chutzpah.; Recording location: Sportsman's.; Alpert 829-830; 1 sound cassette
  - Chutzpah-II, April 20, 1978, AFC 2017/048: SR0438; Personnel: Chutzpah.; Recording location: Sportsman's.; Alpert 831-832; 1 sound cassette
  - Leo Rosner and his music, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0442; Personnel: Leo Rosner.; Alpert 837-838; 1 sound cassette
  - Vermont Friends II; Marlis and Cornelia Kraft, August 31, 1983-December 1984, AFC 2017/048: SR0443; Personnel: Mary Cay, Meghan Merker, Michael Alpert, Moly Mason, Pete Jung.; Alpert 839-840; 1 sound cassette
  - Some Kinda Klezmer BBC Broadcast, September 7, 1997, AFC 2017/048: SR0446; Alpert 845-846; 1 sound cassette
  - Khusidl, February 1999, AFC 2017/048: SR0450; Personnel: Brian Bender, Sruli Dresner, Lisa Mayer, David Krakauer.; Recording location: Tonic.; Alpert 852-853; 1 sound cassette
  - Leonard Koenig-I, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0455; Alpert 861-862; 1 sound cassette
  - Leonard Koenig-II, undated, AFC 2017/048: SR0456; Alpert 863-864; 1 sound cassette